<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>HZzzzB&#39;s Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Memories</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-26T07:32:24.640Z</updated>
  <id>https://hzzzzb.co/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>HZzzzB</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>STL Remove 的用法</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/26/2017-07-26-Remove/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/26/2017-07-26-Remove/</id>
    <published>2017-07-26T07:31:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-26T07:32:24.640Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a id="more"></a>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;a id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="C++ 语法" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/C-%E8%AF%AD%E6%B3%95/"/>
    
    
      <category term="C++ STL" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/C-STL/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>深入理解 yield 语法</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/26/2017-07-26-yield-in-python/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/26/2017-07-26-yield-in-python/</id>
    <published>2017-07-26T01:22:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-26T07:23:34.119Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a id="more"></a>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;a id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Python 语法" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/Python-%E8%AF%AD%E6%B3%95/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Python" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/Python/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Scrapy Learning (1)</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/25/2017-07-25-Scrapy-Learning/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/25/2017-07-25-Scrapy-Learning/</id>
    <published>2017-07-25T02:30:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-26T06:24:47.868Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scrapy is an application framework for crawling web sites and extracting structured data which can be used for a wide range of useful applications, like data mining, information processing or historical archival.<br>Even though Scrapy was originally designed for web scraping, it can also be used to extract data using APIs (such as Amazon Associates Web Services) or as a general purpose web crawler.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="初窥Scrapy"><a href="#初窥Scrapy" class="headerlink" title="初窥Scrapy"></a>初窥Scrapy</h1><p><strong>Scrapy</strong> 使用了 <strong>Twisted</strong> 异步网络库来处理网络通讯。</p>
<p>其架构为：</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/1utP7Sv.png" alt=""></p>
<p>组件：<br><div class="note default"><p>引擎(Scrapy): 用来处理整个系统的数据流处理, 触发事务(框架核心)<br>调度器(Scheduler): 用来接受引擎发过来的请求, 压入队列中, 并在引擎再次请求的时候返回. 可以想像成一个URL（抓取网页的网址或者说是链接）的优先队列, 由它来决定下一个要抓取的网址是什么, 同时去除重复的网址<br>下载器(Downloader): 用于下载网页内容, 并将网页内容返回给蜘蛛(Scrapy下载器是建立在twisted这个高效的异步模型上的)<br>爬虫(Spiders): 爬虫是主要干活的, 用于从特定的网页中提取自己需要的信息, 即所谓的实体(Item)。用户也可以从中提取出链接,让Scrapy继续抓取下一个页面<br>项目管道(Pipeline): 负责处理爬虫从网页中抽取的实体，主要的功能是持久化实体、验证实体的有效性、清除不需要的信息。当页面被爬虫解析后，将被发送到项目管道，并经过几个特定的次序处理数据。<br>下载器中间件(Downloader Middlewares): 位于Scrapy引擎和下载器之间的框架，主要是处理Scrapy引擎与下载器之间的请求及响应。<br>爬虫中间件(Spider Middlewares): 介于Scrapy引擎和爬虫之间的框架，主要工作是处理蜘蛛的响应输入和请求输出。<br>调度中间件(Scheduler Middewares): 介于Scrapy引擎和调度之间的中间件，从Scrapy引擎发送到调度的请求和响应</p>
</div></p>
<p>Scrapy 运行流程：<br><div class="note default"><p>首先，引擎从调度器中取出一个链接(URL)用于接下来的抓取<br>引擎把URL封装成一个请求(Request)传给下载器，下载器把资源下载下来，并封装成应答包(Response)<br>然后，爬虫解析Response<br>若是解析出实体（Item）,则交给实体管道进行进一步的处理。<br>若是解析出的是链接（URL）,则把URL交给Scheduler等待抓取</p>
</div></p>
<h1 id="安装指南"><a href="#安装指南" class="headerlink" title="安装指南"></a>安装指南</h1><h2 id="安装-Scrapy"><a href="#安装-Scrapy" class="headerlink" title="安装 Scrapy"></a>安装 Scrapy</h2><p>Scrapy runs on Python 2.7 and Python 3.3 or above.</p>
<p>在 Window 10 下， 推荐使用 Anaconda 或是 Miniconda. You can install the package from the conda-forge channel<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">conda install -c conda-forge scrapy</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<h1 id="Scrapy-Tutorial"><a href="#Scrapy-Tutorial" class="headerlink" title="Scrapy Tutorial"></a>Scrapy Tutorial</h1><h2 id="创建项目"><a href="#创建项目" class="headerlink" title="创建项目"></a>创建项目</h2><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">scrapy startproject picture-crawler</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Scrapy is an application framework for crawling web sites and extracting structured data which can be used for a wide range of useful applications, like data mining, information processing or historical archival.&lt;br&gt;Even though Scrapy was originally designed for web scraping, it can also be used to extract data using APIs (such as Amazon Associates Web Services) or as a general purpose web crawler.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Python 项目" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/Python-%E9%A1%B9%E7%9B%AE/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Scrapy" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/Scrapy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>To be the Best of Yourself</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/23/To-be-the-Best-of-Yourself/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/23/To-be-the-Best-of-Yourself/</id>
    <published>2017-07-23T15:25:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-26T07:18:10.654Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="blockquote-center"><p> To me, you are still nothing more than a little boy who is just like a hundred thousand other little boys. And I have no need of you. And you, on your part, have no need of me. To you, I am nothing more than a fox like a hundred thousand other foxes. But if you tame me, then we shall need each other. To me, you will be unique in all the world. To you, I shall be unique in all the world。</p>
<p><strong><em>The Little Prince</em></strong> </p>
</blockquote>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>From:<br><a href="https://www.quora.com/What-can-I-do-to-make-sure-I-am-becoming-the-best-version-of-myself" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.quora.com/What-can-I-do-to-make-sure-I-am-becoming-the-best-version-of-myself</a></p>
<h2 id="One"><a href="#One" class="headerlink" title="One"></a>One</h2><span itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img itemprop="url image" src="http://i.imgur.com/ogP8PUM.jpg" class="full-image" alt="alt"><meta itemprop="width" content="auto"><meta itemprop="height" content="auto"></span>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Just show up</strong>. Say you want to run a marathon, but have no prior experience. The first step is lacing up you shoes and hitting the pavement. Even if you only make it half a mile on your first training run, you’ll be about 2% closer to your ultimate goal than if you didn’t put in any work at all. </p>
</div>
<div class="note primary"><p><strong>Start from the beginning</strong>. You don’t just happen to stumble upon the best version of yourself. You need to start from the beginning and take a high number of small steps in order to become what you envision. </p>
</div>
<div class="note success"><p><strong>Recognize that the best version of yourself should be your vision, not anybody else’s</strong>. Don’t waste energy trying to live up to what somebody else wants you to be. </p>
</div>
<div class="note info"><p><strong>Stop looking for a secret trick</strong>. There is no miraculous shortcut to the better version of yourself. </p>
</div>
<div class="note warning"><p><strong>Use Twitter to network</strong>. It’s never been easier to get in touch with influential and powerful people. Earlier in my career, I reached out a high-level executive of a company I was interested in. He was hosting an AMA session on Twitter. I asked him for advice about how to get hired for his company, and not only did he reply with some helpful tips, he also connected me with specific people at the company about an open position. </p>
</div>
<div class="note danger"><p><strong>Don’t sweat the details</strong>. Just make sure that you’re moving in the right general direction. You probably don’t have the knowledge you need today to know the shortest path to your happiness 5 years from today. But you probably have some idea about how to move in the right direction. Take those steps. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Recognize the opportunity at hand</strong>. The Internet has fundamentally changed everything. Previously, knowledge was locked away in the minds of industry experts and in the pages of books that you needed to buy or check out from a library. But now, it’s easier than ever to learn new skills. This is essential to becoming the best version of yourself. </p>
</div>

<div class="note default"><p><strong>Write on Medium</strong>. Translating your thoughts into written narratives pushes you to think about the ideas in your head at a much deeper level. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Don’t count the hours</strong>. They don’t matter. Think about the last time you ran on a treadmill. If you looked down at the timer every few seconds, you probably didn’t enjoy your run. In turn, this made it far more difficult to run far. </p>
</div>
<p>But what if you took the opposite approach? You plugged in your headphones, lost yourself in the music, and took it one stride at a time….while resisting any temptation to look at the timer at all. If you did this, you probably discovered that you enjoyed the run and made it pretty far. Counting hours just slows you down from reaching your goal. </p>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Accept help from other people</strong>. Don’t let your pride get in the way. Most successful people needed help along the way, too. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Launch a personal website</strong>. Maintaining an online presence of yourself pushes you to become the best possible version of you. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Write answers on Quora</strong>. Quora is an amazing place to help and inspire people at scale. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Ignore the social media scoreboard</strong>. People depict an extremely exaggerated version of life on Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, and other social platforms. We only share the good things, not the bad. So when you compare yourself to what you see on social media, you’re just hurting yourself. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Celebrate the small wins</strong>. Appreciating what you’re doing in the present gives you the motivation to keep making strides towards your ultimate goal. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Stop pretending to know things you don’t know</strong>. You’ll never learn anything if you pretend to already know everything. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Embrace failure</strong>. You can’t become the best version of yourself by playing it safe. Heck, getting fired could even be the best thing that ever happened to you, just look at Noah Kagan (employee 30 at Facebook). </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Call your family</strong>. This is just the decent thing to do. But you can also learn lessons from your family that aren’t available through any Google search and aren’t accessible to pretty much anyone else in the world. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Exercise in the morning</strong>. Once I started doing this in the morning, I became far more focused and relaxed throughout the day. Science backs that up, too. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Create a side project</strong>. Doing something productive outside of work that makes you happy helps you become a better version of yourself. So, whatever it is…an app, film, album, whatever….start doing it on your nights and weekends. And who knows? It might just turn into a full-time job that you love. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Help other people become the best version of themselves</strong>. Pay it forward. Doing so keep you motivated on your own path, and you’ll find that the lasting connections you build from helping others will greatly benefit you moving forward. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Launch your MVP early</strong>. If you’re not satisfied with the current version of yourself, then the quickest way to solve the problem is to begin working towards the better version today. There is no “right time” to get started. </p>
</div>
<p>It can be tempting to think about the best version of yourself as some intangible point in the future. You know, the one where you are:</p>
<p>More successful<br>Doing what you love<br>Existing as an overall happier person<br>You see your current self as the regular season, and you’re just waiting for the playoffs to start before giving it your all.</p>
<p>But if all you do is wait for the best version of yourself to happen, you’re forever going to be stuck with the current version.</p>
<p>So, how do you launch the best version of yourself? Start making progress today.</p>
<p>Sometimes, you need to make a big change in order to unleash the best version of yourself. If one thought recently entered your mind, then it’s time to do it.</p>
<h2 id="Two"><a href="#Two" class="headerlink" title="Two"></a>Two</h2><span itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img itemprop="url image" src="http://i.imgur.com/uRCmU9W.jpg" class="full-image" alt="alt"><meta itemprop="width" content="auto"><meta itemprop="height" content="auto"></span>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Observe yourself</strong>. Watch your actions, habits, what makes you happy, what pisses you off, how do you behave in crisis, what sustains you, what drains you etc. Observe yourself over the course of the day or a week. (You can make a funny writing exercise out of it. Here is the prompt.) Then you can proceed to next ideas. Observation is the starting point. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Identify your bad habits</strong>. Start eliminating or mitigating them slowly. You might not even be aware of the amount of time you spend in front of TV, scrolling mindlessly over your Facebook feed. You may not realize how often you grab a midnight snack. Observe yourself first. Then work on eliminating at least some of the habits that squander your time, energy, creativity, health. I wrote more about changing bad habits HERE.</p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Create a routine that helps you show up in a best way</strong>. What all high-performers have in common is a routine, a set of habits, that they perform every day no matter what. These habits help them show up at their best every day, without significant fluctuations in mood of performance. Some examples: 8 hours of sleep, meditation, glass of green juice in the morning, any kind of spiritual practice, writing 10 ideas every day, exercising etc. Define what are the things that, when done regularly, help you show up at your best. Create your optimal routine. Prioritize it. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Focus</strong>. Whatever you do (and I’m sure you will do many things and wear many hats on the daily basis), focus. If you cook, cook. If you study, study. Multitasking is fancy term for doing more things poorly at the same time. Focused work is the least tiresome and the most productive type of work. “Winners focus, losers spray,” said Michael LeBouf, the author of “The Millionaire in You”. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Slow down</strong>. I claim slowing down is a one thing that changed my life in most magnificent ways. Slowing down will help you understand yourself and others better, have better reactions in any situation, do any type of work in a better way. (And HERE are some more reasons why slowing down can help you become better YOU.) </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Use the resources that you have right now</strong>. We are so often stuck in stories: “If only I had XYZ, I would…” How about starting from where you are? How about using what you already have? I know hundreds of people that have fancy cameras they never take with themselves. Isn’t that a pity? How many wonderful moments will just slip? How often we whine for the newest phone/camera/game/course/book/shoes forgetting about the ton of stuff we already have? Grab the camera that you have, put on your running shoes, explore your neighborhood, do something interesting today. Fancier gadgets won’t make you better. Action will. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Be yourself</strong>. Unapologetically. Focus on your strengths. Leverage your contrasts. Be a weirdo. Be different. You are awesome. In her book “Happiness Project”, Gretchen Rubin created her own commandments and the firs one was “Be Gretchen”. The significance of this commandment was great, she basically encouraged herself to follow her intuition and her own rules in many situations. She stopped forcing herself to enjoy music, food, parties just because the society puts emphasis on these things. She let herself love what she loves. “Becoming YOU is your life purpose,” said Danielle Laporte. Welcome home. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Implement</strong>. Let’s say you want to loose the weight and I give you 10 diet books. Which one will help you the most? The answer: the one you actually implement. (OK, we can discuss food science in more detail, but that’s not the point here.) You will receive tons of great tips and ideas here on Quora and elsewhere. But only the tips that you implement will make a difference in your life. Read, explore, come up with ideas. But don’t forget to implement. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Foster your relationships</strong>. Call your parents, siblings, friends. Be there for them. Be generous. Open your heart, your mind, your wallet. Make someone’s day. Show your gratitude. Give a praise. Give a support. Accept. Don’t judge. Love. There will always be more work to do and more dishes to wash. Share your love and care today. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Laugh</strong>. (Last but not the least.) Start with laughing at yourself. Talk crap with your friends and laugh together. Watch a comedy. Read jokes. Relax. “Laughter is more essential for the survival than fighting,” said James Altucher. And it will certainly pull out the best from you. </p>
</div>
<p>Let’s wrap this story up with a beautiful quote by Ernest Hemingway : “There is nothing noble in being superior to your fellow man; true nobility is being superior to your former self.” </p>
<h2 id="Three"><a href="#Three" class="headerlink" title="Three"></a>Three</h2><span itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img itemprop="url image" src="http://i.imgur.com/DmTRqUB.jpg" class="full-image" alt="alt"><meta itemprop="width" content="auto"><meta itemprop="height" content="auto"></span>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Respect Yourself</strong> - To respect yourself means to deny yourself. Fighting bad food cravings, working on projects instead of partying all night, or even disassociating yourself from toxic people are all part of the process. Respect yourself, your life, and what you have to offer. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Seek Education</strong> - The responsibility of being an educated individual falls solely on you. School alone doesn’t make you educated. Stay current on the news and the climate of the world we live in. Read books and invest in self improvement practices. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Learn The Power of “No”</strong> - Strong and powerful people know where to draw the line by not compromising their values. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Emotional Maturity</strong> - Becoming a better version of yourself involves controlling your emotions. Learn to not be overtaken by them and thoroughly analyze a situation before reacting immediately. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Honesty</strong> - Be more honest with others but more importantly, be honest with yourself. Do you love your job/friends/relationship? Do you dislike your job/friends/relationship? Being honest allows you to make the decisions that properly suit your needs. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Stop Caring So Much</strong> - Stop worrying and caring so much about everything going on around you. Most of those things are out of your control and worrying about them isn’t going to change the outcome. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Fall In Love With Life</strong> - Technology has made it even easier to forget just how beautiful life is. Take time to appreciate the grand beauties of our earth and the broad and vast number of wonders we can experience in our lifetime. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Fall In Love With Yourself</strong> - You are special and nobody that has ever existed is like you. Appreciate what you have to offer because it is unique and don’t ever let anyone make you think otherwise. </p>
</div>
<h2 id="Four"><a href="#Four" class="headerlink" title="Four"></a>Four</h2><span itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img itemprop="url image" src="http://i.imgur.com/RJWhNpv.jpg" class="full-image" alt="alt"><meta itemprop="width" content="auto"><meta itemprop="height" content="auto"></span>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Be ready to shred your old self completely</strong>.<br>Becoming the best version of yourself means that you’re going to move away from where you are, so you must be willing to shred your old self. When you’re raising your own bar, you’re essentially creating a gap between you and people around you. Your old self is going to resist that - don’t let the resistance get its way.<br>Let go of certainty and embrace uncertainty instead. Nothing is certain, after all. The earlier you realize this, the more you can improve. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Acknowledge your fear</strong>. Then, tame it like a master.<br>Most people are unable to even take action because of fear. Don’t let it limit you. Admit that you’re fearful, but proceed anyway. Anyone who say he has no fear is not telling you the full story. The full story is, he has tamed his fear.<br>The things you’re looking forward could be just right at the edge of your comfort zone. Be courageous. It’s okay to make mistakes - as long as you don’t make the foolhardy ones. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Vigorous self-education</strong>. Read. Get Mentors. Observe. Experiment.<br>The best people never stop learning. If you want to be the best version of yourself, do what they do. “Formal education will make you a living, but self-education will make you a fortune” — Jim Rohn.<br>Never let school interfere your education. Actively educate yourself about topics which can bring you to your greatest height and all your heart into it. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Prioritize output over input</strong>. Don’t get trapped in eternal study!<br>You can never consume all information, strategies and tactics available. Gathering input is necessary, but it means nothing without output. On the other hand, scarcity creates value. What are scarce? Massive action. Shipping. Delivery. Impact.<br>In short, outputs are scarce. Be conscious about your input/output ratio. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Think long term</strong> - like 10 years down the road.<br>It’s always easier to enjoy watching TV compared to hitting the gym. Most people cling to instant gratification, because it feels good in the short run. However, the opportunity cost is huge. When you spend an hour on mindless TV watching, you could have read a book which will potentially increase your income by 50%. In other words, you sacrifice that amount of income increment to watch pointless cat videos.<br>Learn to postpone immediate pleasures for long-term values. The ROI will be phenomenal. Put opportunity cost into your perspective. Things won’t go exactly as planned, but having a big-picture vision helps you move towards the direction you want. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Be 1% better everyday</strong>. After a year, you’ll be 3700% better.<br>Do the math. It’s 3778.34%, to be more accurate. People aim for unrealistic growth over the short term, especially when they’re super motivated. The problem is, that’s not sustainable.<br>Since you’re looking for long term improvement, consider making compounding effect your best friend. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Amplify your strengths</strong>. You can be anything, but you can’t be everything.<br>If you have strengths, amplify them. For example, I have decent English writing and communication skills, and I use these strengths to teach English classes. The classes turn out to be quite successful.<br>If you have certain weaknesses, build a team with complementary skills to cover your weakness. Don’t waste too much time correcting your weakness when someone else can handle the part for you. Amplify your strengths. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Form your success cabinet and shoot for the stars.</strong><br>You’re the average of five people you spend the most time with, because that’s who you subconsciously set benchmark against. To reach maximum height, you’ll need a group of high performance, trustworthy people around you. They will your benchmarks at least 10x higher. I call them the success cabinet.<br>Form your own success cabinet and find ways to bring value to the table. Lift each other up. Cultivate genuine relationships. By doing so you’ll improve immensely. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Give what you have</strong>. What are you rich at? Figure that out.<br>You may think that you have nothing to give, but in fact you do. Everyone is rich in some way. Things you can give include money, smiles, inspiration, confidence, skills, arts, musics, jokes, free rides, services, expertise, past experience, wisdom and many, many more. So yeah, you must be rich at something.<br>Giving what you have forces you to tap into your potential - What do you have in abundance that people are looking for? The more you give, the more you get. But don’t focus on what you’ll get. Just give, give, give. I was reluctant to give, but now I realize that giving is one of the most fulfilling things I can do. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Solve real problems and adjust along the way.</strong><br>Solving imaginary problems can be helpful, but it’s often fear and procrastination in disguise. Well, I made this mistake and wasted months. If you’re doing the same, get out of your head and solve real problems instead. If you fail, good. You’ve identified a way which doesn’t work. You’ve learnt something. Now, go out and do it again. Reiterate until success.<br>Along the way, you’ll also learn how to make adjustments. Every master was once a disaster. Keep doing this and you’ll find ways to offer value and be a linchpin. It’s not easy, but achievable. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Make journal.</strong> Help your brain to keep up with its thoughts.<br>A human has 50,000 to 70,000 thoughts per day. Let’s assume 99% of the thoughts are crappy, we still have 500 to 700 (1%) valuable thoughts per day. We can’t keep up with all our thoughts. Hence I always journal my thoughts so I can work on them later.<br>Get your notebooks handy. Or simply make notes in your mobile phones or laptops. Evernote and Trello are there to help you. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Build momentum smartly.</strong> Think big, start small.<br>People tend to overestimate what they can do in a day, but underestimate what they can do it a year. Becoming the best version yourself is a marathon, not a sprint. If you sprint, you’ll be gasping for breath pretty soon.<br>Think big, start small. Stop thinking about starting. Just. Start. </p>
</div>
<div class="note default"><p><strong>Last but not least, be macro-patient, micro-aggressive</strong>.<br>Live your everyday to the fullest by doing what’s necessary. Learn to differentiate what’s within and beyond your circle of control. Once you’ve done your best, what happens, happens. Be patient and keep grinding.<br>As long as you’re working in the right direction, things will work out. The most important of all, enjoy the journey - even if it sucks sometimes. </p>
</div>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote-center&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt; To me, you are still nothing more than a little boy who is just like a hundred thousand other little boys. And I have no need of you. And you, on your part, have no need of me. To you, I am nothing more than a fox like a hundred thousand other foxes. But if you tame me, then we shall need each other. To me, you will be unique in all the world. To you, I shall be unique in all the world。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="人生哲思" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/%E4%BA%BA%E7%94%9F%E5%93%B2%E6%80%9D/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Self-Improvement" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/Self-Improvement/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>基于GitHub Pages 和 Hexo 搭建简单博客</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/21/%E5%9F%BA%E4%BA%8EGitHub-Pages-%E5%92%8C-Hexo-%E6%90%AD%E5%BB%BA%E7%AE%80%E5%8D%95%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/21/基于GitHub-Pages-和-Hexo-搭建简单博客/</id>
    <published>2017-07-21T13:32:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-23T13:39:35.073Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在 Window 10 下， 基于GitHub Pages 和 Hexo 搭建简单博客。 主要采用了 NexT 这款简洁的主题(<a href="https://github.com/iissnan" target="_blank" rel="external">作者</a>)。 “工欲善其事必先利其器”， 让我们一步一步来搭建出属于自己的简单博客， がんばってください！</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>必要的网址：<a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Github Pages</a>, <a href="https://hexo.io/zh-cn/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo</a>, <a href="https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next" target="_blank" rel="external">主题 NexT</a>, <a href="http://theme-next.iissnan.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">NexT 文档</a></p>
<p>必要的环境与软件：<a href="https://git-scm.com/downloads" target="_blank" rel="external">Git</a>, <a href="https://nodejs.org/zh-cn/" target="_blank" rel="external">Node.js</a><br>Windows 下安装软件双击安装程序即可</p>
<p>参考：<a href="https://linghucong.js.org/2016/04/15/2016-04-15-hexo-github-pages-blog/" target="_blank" rel="external">https://linghucong.js.org/2016/04/15/2016-04-15-hexo-github-pages-blog/</a></p>
<h2 id="安装-Hexo"><a href="#安装-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="安装 Hexo"></a>安装 Hexo</h2><p>打开Git Bash, 输入<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">cd /d</div><div class="line">npm install hexo-cli -g    # 安装 Hexo</div><div class="line">hexo init MyBlog</div><div class="line">npm install</div><div class="line">hexo g</div><div class="line">hexo s</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<p>通过 <a href="http://localhost:4000/" target="_blank" rel="external">http://localhost:4000/</a>, 看到内置主题的博客</p>
<h2 id="设置-Hexo-主题-NexT"><a href="#设置-Hexo-主题-NexT" class="headerlink" title="设置 Hexo 主题 (NexT):"></a>设置 Hexo 主题 (NexT):</h2><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">cd MyBlog</div><div class="line">git clone https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next themes/next</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>（<a href="http://theme-next.iissnan.com/getting-started.html" target="_blank" rel="external">参考</a>）</p>
<h2 id="部署-Hexo-到-Github-Pages"><a href="#部署-Hexo-到-Github-Pages" class="headerlink" title="部署 Hexo 到 Github Pages"></a>部署 Hexo 到 Github Pages</h2><p>注册 GitHub 账号（假设账号名为：username, 可根据自己喜好设置用户名）. </p>
<p>创建仓库名为： username.github.io， username 一定得和 GitHub 账号一致（为了能够使用 username.github.io 作为域名直接访问自己的博客， GitHub Pages 官网上强调了）。</p>
<p>需要学习将项目托管到 GitHub 上。<a href="http://1ke.co/course/194" target="_blank" rel="external">参考</a></p>
<p>部署到 GitHub 上的准备：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">npm install hexo-deployer-git --save</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<p>部署到 GitHub，需要在配置文件_config.xml中作如下修改 (注意那个 .git 后缀)：</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">deploy:</div><div class="line">  type: git</div><div class="line">  repo: git@github.com:username/username.github.io.git</div><div class="line">  branch: master</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>将之前创建的博客仓库克隆到本地：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">cd /d/MyBlog</div><div class="line">git clone https://github.com/username/username.github.io.git .deploy/username.github.io</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<p>创建一个部署博客的脚本(blog-deploy.sh)：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">hexo generate</div><div class="line">cp -R public/* .deploy/username.github.io</div><div class="line">cd .deploy/username.github.io</div><div class="line">git add .</div><div class="line">git commit -m “update blog”</div><div class="line">git push origin master</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<p>执行过程中可能需要让你输入Github账户的用户名及密码，按照提示操作即可。</p>
<h2 id="创建博客文章"><a href="#创建博客文章" class="headerlink" title="创建博客文章"></a>创建博客文章</h2><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">cd /d/MyBlog</div><div class="line">hexo new &quot;My-First-Blog&quot;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>然后在 D:\MyBlog\source_posts 下修改对应的 .md 文件即可。</p>
<p>文章的开头都形如：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">title: My First Blog</div><div class="line">date: 2017-07-21 10:32:26</div><div class="line">tags: My-First-Blog</div><div class="line">categories: 教程</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>
<h2 id="享受写作-Enjoy-it"><a href="#享受写作-Enjoy-it" class="headerlink" title="享受写作(Enjoy it!)"></a>享受写作(Enjoy it!)</h2><p>关于写作格式: <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax/" target="_blank" rel="external">参考</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;在 Window 10 下， 基于GitHub Pages 和 Hexo 搭建简单博客。 主要采用了 NexT 这款简洁的主题(&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iissnan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;作者&lt;/a&gt;)。 “工欲善其事必先利其器”， 让我们一步一步来搭建出属于自己的简单博客， がんばってください！&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="教程" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/%E6%95%99%E7%A8%8B/"/>
    
    
      <category term="GitHub-Hexo" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/GitHub-Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/21/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://hzzzzb.co/2017/07/21/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2017-07-21T02:32:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-21T14:00:16.592Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="external">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="external">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>.<br><a id="more"></a></p>
<h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">"My New Post"</span></div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Writing</a></p>
<h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo server</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Server</a></p>
<h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo generate</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Generating</a></p>
<h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo deploy</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Deployment</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;! This is your very first post. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; or you can ask me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="教程" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/categories/%E6%95%99%E7%A8%8B/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hello-My-Blog" scheme="https://hzzzzb.co/tags/Hello-My-Blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
